《黑夜传说》
战争, 一眨眼的功夫就停止了
The war had all but ground to a halt in the blink of an eye.
卢西恩, 狼人中最可怕及残暴的领袖
Lucian, the most feared and ruthless leader ever to rule the Lycan clan...
终于被杀
...had finally been killed.
那是在一个充满了火焰和复仇的夜晚
The Lycan horde scattered to the wind...
狼人族从此变成游民随风流亡
...in a single evening of flame and retribution.
表面看来我们已经胜利
Victory, it seemed, was in our grasp...
吸血鬼终于可以安然存活
...the very birthright of the Vampires.
那晚之后, 转眼又过了六个世纪
Nearly six centuries had passed since that night.
那远古的血腥争斗却没有跟随卢西恩一起进入坟墓
Yet the ancient feud proved unwilling to follow Lucian to the grave.
尽管狼人的数目已减少
Though Lycans were fewer in number...
但战争本身还是越来越危险
...the war itself had become more perilous.
不再受月亮的控制
For the moon no longer held her sway.
古老强大的狼人可以随意改变身体
Older, more powerful Lycans were now able to change at will.
虽然武器进步了, 但是我们的目标仍旧是
The weapons had evolved, but our orders remained the same
狩猎他们, 杀死他们, 一个接一个
Hunt them down and kill them off, one by one.
最成功的战役
A most successful campaign.
可能太过成功
Perhaps too successful.
对我这样一个死亡行者而言
For those like me, a Death Dealer...
这标志着一个时代的结束
...this signaled the end of an era.
就如同上个世纪的武器一样
Like the weapons of the previous century...
我们同样会被废弃
...we, too, would become obsolete.
真可惜, 因为我靠它而活
Pity, because I lived for it.
吸血鬼！
Bloods!
没事, 没事, 你会好起来的
It's all right. It's all right. You're gonna be okay.
你们就像是一群疯狗！
You're acting like a pack of rabid dogs!
那么, 各位
And that, gentlemen...
以后别这么做
...simply will not do.
除非你想在吸血鬼的地盘上打垮他们
Not if you expect to defeat the Vampires on their own ground.
除非你想活下来
Not if you expect to survive at all.
皮尔斯！泰勒！
Pierce! Taylor!
把衣服穿上好吗？
Put some clothes on, will you?
我们遇到个严重的问题
We have a serious problem.
我得做些试验了
I'll have to run a few tests.
它肯定是某种光子流的
It's definitely an irradiated fluid of some sort.
紫外线武器
Ultraviolet ammunition.
利用日光作为武器
Daylight, harnessed as a weapon.
你想让我相信一个恶心的怪物
You expect me to believe that a mangy animal...
会用高科技装备的子弹去射杀吸血鬼？
...came up with a bullet specifically engineered to kill Vampires?
不, 我打赌那是军用技术
No, I'm betting it's military.
他们偷了些东西, 一些高科技追踪装置
Something they stole. Some sort of high-tech tracer round.
我不关心他们从哪儿得到这些玩意儿
I don't care where they got these things.
瑞吉儿死了, 纳撒尼尔还在外边
Rigel is dead, and Nathaniel could still be out there.
集合所有的死亡行者, 撤退
We should gather the Death Dealers and get back down therefore
不能撤…不能因为一次偶然入侵就撤退
Absolutely not. Not now. Not for a random incursion.
唤醒是几天后的事, 这所房子已动荡不安
The Awakening is a few days off, and this house is in unrest as it is.
偶然的？大家都看见了他们在向我们开火
Random? They opened fire on us in full view of the public.
- 而且我在那条隧道里听到了 - 你说过你什么都没看到
- And from what I heard in that tunnel... - You said you didn't see anything.
我清楚听到什么, 也知道心里想什么
I know what I heard, and I know what my gut tells me.
下面有一大群狼人
And I am telling you there could be dozens of Lycans down there.
可能更多, 谁知道, 也许成百上千
Who knows, maybe more. Hundreds.
经过我们的猎杀, 他们几近灭绝
We've hunted them to the brink of extinction.
克莱恩是对的, 瑟琳娜
Kraven's right, Selene.
很久以来都没有过那么大的洞穴了
There's not been a den of that magnitude for centuries.
- 自从卢西恩时代起就没有过 - 这我知道, 卡恩
- Not since the days of Lucian.  - I know that, Kahn.
但我希望在你检查之后, 再告诉我那不是真的
But I'd rather you prove me wrong by checking it out.
好吧 让你的人待命！
Very well.Have your men tighten things up.
我会让索伦组织一个搜索小队
I'll have Soren assemble a search team.
- 不, 我来带队吧 - 绝对不行, 让索伦负责
- No, I want to lead the team myself.  - Absolutely not! Soren will handle it.
上百只, 真的那么多吗？
Hundreds, really?
维克多会相信我的
Viktor would believe me.
- 我从没那样对待过你 - 没错
- I'd never treat you like that.  - Of course not.
现在去看看她是否打扮好能够见客人了
Now run along and make sure she's dressed and ready for her guests.
- 你知道, 这是在浪费时间 - 什么意思？
- It's a waste of time, you know. - What is?
我怀疑维克多想让你在这一直盯着他的坟墓
I doubt Viktor would want you freezing in here, staring at his tomb for hours.
不, 他是想让死亡行者去搜索城市
No, he'd want the Death Dealers out there, scouring every inch of the city.
克莱恩, 我搞不懂为什么维克多让他负责这事
Kraven. I'll never understand why Viktor left him in charge.
他是个官僚, 不是个战士
He's a bureaucrat, not a warrior.
我们希望你准备好了
Come on, We need to get you ready.
- 为了什么？ - 舞会
- For what?  - The party.
阿米莉亚的使节随时随地都会出现
Amelia's envoy will be here any minute.
哦, 没错
Oh, yes.
你一定得穿上这个, 真是完美
You should definitely wear this one. It's perfect.
他们要找的是你
They were after you.
他很有魅力
He's attractive...
- 作为一个人来说 - 谁很有魅力？
- ...for a human.  - Who's attractive?
今天晚上我计划让你在我身边待着
You know I planned to have you at my side this evening.
带上艾丽卡, 她渴望在你身边
Take Erika. She's dying to be at your side.
如果你问我, 我要说你把战斗看得太重了
If you ask me, you take this warrior business far too seriously.
你无法改变过去, 无论你杀了多少人
You can't undo the past, no matter how many you kill.
除此之外
And besides...
如果你拒绝生活中简单的乐趣的话
...what's the point in being immortal...
永生又有什么意义呢
...if you deny yourself life's simple pleasures?
你看见这个人了吗？
Do you see this human?
- 怎么了？ - 我感觉是狼人
- What of him?  - I'm beginning to think the Lycans...
该死！
Blast!
快点穿的端庄高贵些
Put on something elegant and be quick about it.
克莱恩, 我是认真的, 我觉得他们在跟着他
Kraven, I'm serious. I think they were following him.
除了获取食物, 狼人跟踪人类干嘛？
Other than food, why would Lycans stalk a human?
有进展吗？
Any progress?
让我们瞧瞧
Let's find out.
没有
Negative.
你回家？
You heading home?
是啊, 尼古拉斯给了我几个小时的假
Yeah, Nicholas gave me a couple hours off.
另外
By the way...
他说今晚你在手术室干得不错
...he said you did a terrific job tonight with the surgery.
当然
Yeah.
放轻松点
Take it easy.
我们被伏击了
We were ambushed.
三个死亡行者
Death Dealers, three of them.
- 那个目标呢？ - 我们跟丢了
- And the candidate?  - We lost him.
你跟丢了？
You lost him?
看看这个
Look at this mess.
银球, 银含量很高
Ag rounds. High content.
阻止他起变化
Prevented him from making the change.
挖出其它的也没用了, 银已穿透他组织器官
No use in digging out the rest. Silver's penetrated his organs.
现在再想修复已经不可能了
Regeneration's impossible at this point.
把这些东西拿出来
Let's take these out.
放松
Relax.
吸血鬼不会想到你会跟踪一个人类的
The Vampires didn't realize you were following a human...
- 对吧, 瑞兹？ - 不
- ...did they, Raze?  - No.
我的意思是, 我不这么想
I mean, I don't think so.
- 你不这么想, 还是你根本就不知道？ - 我不清楚
- You don't think, or you don't know?  - I'm not sure.
不行
Negative.
我真的要去看看这个迈克尔了
I really must have a look at this Michael.
什么事情都要我亲自动手
Must I do everything myself?
也许我们被大海分割
Our noble houses may be separated by a great ocean...
但是我们有同样的血统
...but we are equally committed to the survival of the bloodlines.
当阿米莉亚到了并唤醒了马库斯时
And when Amelia arrives to awaken Marcus...
只剩两天的时间
...in just two days' time...
我们将会再一次的团结在一起了！
...we shall once again be united as a single coven!
我们想多谢主人的盛情款待
We want to thank our hosts for their generous hospitality.
(姓名：迈克尔·柯文 | 住址：3B街区 510号)
他来了, 他做了他该做的事然后回家
He comes in, he does his job and then he goes home.
除了这些, 我也不知道该告诉你什么了
Other than that, I really don't know what to tell you.
日夜不停地工作, 难道生活中就没别的了
Interns work around the clock. We don't have much of a life.
你知道我们在哪儿能找到他吗？
You know where we can find him?
不知道
No.
你可以到他家去找找, 要不就在这等他回来
You can try him at home, or you'll have to wait till he gets back.
他没遇到什么麻烦吧？
He's not in some kind of trouble, is he?
我是迈克尔, 我现在不在家, 请留下口讯
This is Michael. I'm not in right now. Please leave a message.
迈克尔, 我是亚当, 警察正在医院找你呢
Michael, it's Adam. The police were just in the hospital looking for you.
他们确信你卷入了一场枪击事件
They were convinced you were involved with a shootout.
我告诉他们这不可能
I told them there's no way you'd be involved with that...
但他们还是在找你, 就在现在
...but they're looking for you. Right now.
他们为什么抓你？
Why are they after you?
该死！
Shit!
你好, 迈克尔
Hello, Michael.
他妈的到底发生什么事了？
What the fuck is going on?
停车
Stop the car.
停车！
Stop the car!
后退！
Back off!
好
Okay.
好, 没问题
好吧
All right.
你流了很多血
But you've lost a lot of blood.
如果你不停车的话, 我们都会死的
If you don't stop the car, you'll get us both killed.
- 我不是在胡闹！ - 我也不是！
- I'm not screwing around!  - Neither am I!
闭上你的嘴, 我很好
Shut up and hold on. I'll be fine.
他妈的！
Shit!
又逃脱了, 真是令人印象深刻
A second escape. Impressive.
可能瑞兹没有夸大事实
Perhaps Raze wasn't overstating matters.
瑞兹可没带回这个
Raze didn't bring back this.
如果迈克尔的确是我们要找的人, 那吸血鬼就会...
If Michael is indeed The Carrier, the Vampires could...
别紧张, 老伙计
Relax, old friend.
我尝过他的肉
I've tasted his flesh.
离月圆还有两天
Just two days till full moon.
很快, 他就会成为一个狼人了
Soon, he will be a Lycan.
很快, 他就会来找我们了
Soon, he will come looking for us.
很可惜我们没有更多了
It's a shame we don't have more.
确实如此
Positive.
躺着别动, 你的头被狠狠地敲了一下
Lay still. Your skull's taken a good knock.
你曾短暂昏迷过
You've been unconscious for a while.
你知道为什么那些人追你？
Do you have any idea why those men were after you?
我在哪儿？
Where am I?
这地方很安全
You're safe.
我是瑟琳娜
I'm Selene.
所以, 起码这次谣言是真的
So, for once, the rumors were true.
整间房子的人都对你的新宠议论纷纷
The whole house has been absolutely buzzing about your new pet.
- 你打算把他变成我们同类？ - 当然不是
- Are you going to try to turn him?  - Of course not.
那你为什么把他带到这儿来？
So why did you bring him here?
他救过我
He saved my life.
- 你怎么来这儿了？ - 克莱恩派我来的
- Why are you here?  - Kraven sent me.
他想见你, 现在
He wants to see you. Now.
我不会同意的！
This is completely unacceptable!
你违抗我的命令, 整晚离开
You go against my orders and spend the night away from the mansion...
和一个人类在一起？居然还带到我这里来！
...with a human? A human you've since brought back to my house.
据我所知, 这儿仍是维克多的
As far as I'm concerned, this is still Viktor's house.
你知道, 我不想吵架
Look, I don't want to argue.
你要知道迈克尔对狼人来说有多重要
I just need you understand that Michael is somehow important to the Lycans...
- 现在叫迈克尔了！ - 能先听完我说的话吗？
- So now it's "Michael"!  - Would you just hear me out?
我难以理解为什么你执着于这个荒谬的理论
It's beyond me why you're so obsessed over this ridiculous theory.
卢西恩绝不会对一个人类有丝毫的兴趣
Lucian wouldn't be a bit interested in a human...
无论是迈克尔还是别人
...Michael or otherwise.
等一下
Wait a minute.
他让你着迷了, 对吧？
You're infatuated with him, aren't you?
这想法真荒谬
Now, that's a ridiculous theory.
到底是不是呢？
Is it?
离开这儿！
Leave us!
我希望你不会生我的气
I sure hope you never get pissed off with me.
等等
Hold on.
试试这个
Check this out.
动手吧, 射击
Go ahead. Squeeze off a few.
退出弹夹
Eject the mag.
你已经克隆了狼人的子弹, 硝酸银
You've copied the Lycan rounds. Silver nitrate.
足以致命的剂量
A lethal dose.
他们不能像挖出一般子弹一样挖出这个
They won't dig these out, like our usual rounds.
直接流入血液中, 什么也挖不出来的
Straight into the bloodstream. Ain't nothing to dig out.
告诉我, 卡恩
Tell me, Kahn.
你相信卢西恩是像他们说的那样死了吗？
Do you believe Lucian died the way they say?
- 克莱恩又讲起战争故事了？ - 那是我的看法
- Kraven telling war stories again?  - That's my point.
那只不过是个古老的故事, 他的故事
It's nothing but an ancient story. His story.
除了他说的, 没什么能证明他杀死卢西恩
There's not a shred of proof he killed Lucian, only his word.
我从没低估过克莱恩对进步的渴求程度
I've never underestimated Kraven's lust for advancement...
但是维克多相信他, 那才是重点
...but Viktor believed him and that's all that matters.
- 你要带着这个东西去哪？ - 哪也不去
- Where you going with this anyway?  - Nowhere.
和死亡行者公开交火, 并追击人类
Engaging Death Dealers in public and chasing after some human...
并不是我所想的, 你们应该开个店做掩护！
...was not what I had in mind. You were told to set up shop and lay low!
冷静点, 克莱恩！
Calm yourself, Kraven!
人类跟你无关
The human doesn't concern you.
而且除此之外, 我已经藏头缩尾很久了
And besides, I've laid low for quite long enough.
管好你的人, 卢西恩
Just keep your men at bay, Lucian.
至少从现在开始
At least for the time being.
别逼我为我们的交易后悔
Don't force me to regret our arrangement.
你只要尽好你自己的本份
You just concentrate on your part.
记住, 我已经为你流过一次血了
Remember, I've bled for you once already.
没我, 你什么也做不成
Without me, you'd have nothing.
你一无所有
You'd be nothing.
在进攻卢西恩堡垒的全部勇士中间
Of the scores of brave souls who entered Lucian's fortress...
只有一个吸血鬼幸存下来了, 他就是克莱恩
...a single Vampire survived; Kraven...
他受到丰厚的奖赏, 不仅是因为他制造了大火
...who was richly rewarded for not only setting the great blaze...
还因为他带回了狼人族首领死亡的证据
...but for returning with evidence of the Lycan master's demise...
一块卢西恩胳膊上的有烙印的皮
...the branded skin, cut from Lucian's very arm.
我一直在找你, 他被咬了
I've been looking for you. He's been bitten.
他已经被打上了狼人的标记
Your human, he's been marked by a Lycan.
- 是克莱恩跟你说的吗？ - 不是
- Did Kraven put you up to this?  - No.
我亲眼看见了那个伤口, 我发誓
I saw the wound with my own eyes, I swear it.
但是盟约怎么办？
But what about the Covenant?
你知道, 这个是不允许的
You know it's forbidden!
自从他咬了我之后, 我就
And ever since he bit me, I've been...
我就有了这些幻想和错觉
I've been having these hallucinations and these delusions.
我所知道的就是, 好像我的头裂成两半似的
All I know is, it feels like my skull is splitting in half.
我懂了, 一个成年男子咬了你？
Okay, so a full-grown man bit you?
天哪！
Jesus.
你肯定不是狗咬的吗？
Are you sure this wasn't a dog?
我说过了, 是个人, 是一个人！
I said, it was a man. It was a man.
- 好, 我明白了 - 他当时在追我
- Okay, I got it.  - He was after me.
- 然后地铁里的那个女人 - 什么女人？
- And that woman from the subway...  - What woman?
你到底听没听我说话？她把我当人质！
Haven't you been listening to me? She took me hostage!
好, 我在听
All right.
等一下
Just... Please.
我会帮你弄清楚的, 好吗？我一会就回来
I'll help you get this all sorted out, all right? I'll be right back.
放手, 迈克尔
Let go, Michael.
放手
Let go.
冷静点, 好吗？我一会儿就回来
Just calm down, okay? I'm gonna be back in a minute.
- 我保证 - 好吧
- That's a promise.  - All right.
请原谅我...
Please forgive me...
但是我真的需要你的指导
...but I desperately need your guidance.
卡恩想见你
Kahn wants to see you.
就我所知
To my knowledge...
唤醒仪式从未由像我这种辈分的人执行过
...an Awakening has never been attempted by one such as myself.
长老们都有能力组织他们的记忆和思想
The elders hold the power to organize their memories and thoughts...
变成一个连贯的影像
...into a single, cohesive vision...
和详细的记录
...a detailed record of their reign.
我只希望维克多能听听我的恳求
I can only hope Viktor will hear my plea.
请原谅我, 但我真的需要你的指导
Please forgive me, but I desperately need your guidance.
很抱歉提前唤醒你
I apologize for awakening you ahead of schedule...
我担心我们可能处于非常危机之中
...but I fear we may all be in grave danger.
尤其是你, 我的主人, 你现在是如此虚弱
Especially you, my lord, if left in your weakened state.
因为我相信卢西恩仍活得好好的
For I believe that Lucian is alive and well.
现在就在这个城市里...
Here. Now. In this very city...
他准备在唤醒仪式上攻击我们
...preparing to hit us during the Awakening ceremony.
更让人头痛的是
Even more disturbing...
如果我想的没错
...is that if I'm correct...
克莱恩跟卢西恩是一伙儿的
...it would mean that Kraven is in league with him.
什么事这么急？
What's so pressing?
看这个
Take a look.
瑟琳娜！
Selene!
我要跟瑟琳娜说话！
I want to speak with Selene!
是迈克尔吗？
Is that Michael?
- 是迈克尔吗？ - 到底发生什么事了？
- Is it Michael?  - What the hell is going on?
我到底怎么了？
What's happening to me?
我这就出来
I'm coming out.
如果你去见他, 你就别想再回来了
If you go to him, you'll never be welcome in this house again.
既然维克多醒了, 看他对这件事会怎么说
Now that Viktor's awake, we'll see what he has to say about that.
上车
Get in.
瞧, 我已警告过她了…警告过…可她不听
Look, I warned her. I warned her, but she didn't listen.
- 我本该早点跟你说的 - 说什么？
- I should've told you sooner.  - Told me what?
她的那个人类, 迈克尔
Her human, Michael...
他已经不再是个人类了
...he's not a human at all.
他是个狼人
He's a Lycan.
什么？
What?
什么事这么吵？
What's this ruckus?
别再回来了, 他们会杀了你的, 明白吗？
Never come here again. They'll kill you.Do you understand?
为什么？你们是谁？
Why? Who are you people?
离开这儿
Leave us.
不论你喜不喜欢, 你已加入了一场持续千年的战争
Like it or not, you're in the middle of a war that's raged for 1000 years.
吸血鬼和狼人之间的族仇
A blood feud between Vampires and Lycans.
狼人
Werewolves.
希望你好运
Consider yourself lucky.
不到一个小时, 被咬过的许多人类都会死
Most humans die within an hour of being bitten by an immortal.
我们传播的病毒是致命的
The viruses we transmit are deadly.
如果你咬了我, 我也会变成吸血鬼？
And if you bit me, I'd become a Vampire instead?
不, 你会死
No, you'd die.
被两个种族咬过之后, 没人能幸存下来
No one's ever survived a bite from both species.
其实我该停下车, 然后杀了你
By rights, I'd stop the car and kill you myself...
- 为什么你要帮我？ - 我没有帮你
- Why are you helping me?  - I'm not.
我会跟踪你, 然后杀死你的同类
I track down and kill your kind.
我最想知道…为什么卢西恩这么想得到你
My only interest is finding out why Lucian wants you so badly.
你知道为什么我醒了, 我的仆人？
Do you know why I've been awakened, servant?
不知道, 主人
No, my lord.
- 但我很快就会知道 - 等你找到她的时候
- But I'll soon find out.  - You mean when you find her.
- 是的, 主人 - 你一定要让她来见我
- Yes, my lord.  - You must let her come to me.
我们有很多事要谈, 瑟琳娜和我
We have much to discuss, Selene and I.
她让我看到了很多麻烦事
She has shown me a great many disturbing things.
不过这些事很快就会解决的
Things that will be dealt with soon enough.
家族越来越软弱和堕落了
This coven has grown weak, decadent.
也许我本该换个人处理我的事务
Perhaps I should have left someone else in charge of my affairs.
还有
Still...
她的记忆
...her memories...
仍旧是混乱的
...are chaotic.
对时间没有意识
There's no sense of time.
主人, 请让我去召集支援吧
Please, my lord, let me summon assistance.
你需要的是休息
You're in need of rest.
我已经休息够了
I've rested enough.
你要做的就是召唤马库斯
What you will do is summon Marcus.
但是他仍在休眠, 主人
But he still slumbers, my lord.
阿米莉亚和理事会成员明天夜里到达
Amelia and the Council members are arriving tomorrow night...
以唤醒马库斯
...to awaken Marcus.
不是你, 我的主人
Not you, my lord.
你已经提前整整一个世纪苏醒了
You've been awakened a full century ahead of schedule.
那个婊子背叛了我
That bitch has betrayed me.
现在他知道所有她困扰的事情了
Now he knows everything she's been obsessing about.
等等
Wait.
你能让我相信吗？
Are you to be trusted?
当然
Of course.
20分钟后在我住的地方等我
Meet me in my quarters in 20 minutes.
是时候让你知道一些事情了
It's time I filled you in on a few things.
我看见这些…这些幻象
I'm seeing these things, these hallucinations.
它们不是幻象, 是记忆
They're not hallucinations, they're memories.
你被咬过了, 他的记忆已经传递给你了
You've been bitten. His memories have been passed to you.
这是我们用来审问的地方之一, 很安全的
This is one of the places we use for interrogations. It should be safe.
- 苏迪斯产业公司 -  我们的产业
- Ziodex Industries.  - We own it.
起先是人造血浆, 现在就是这个
First there was synthetic plasma, now this.
一旦被许可, 它就会成为我们的最新商品
Once it's approved, it should be our newest cash crop.
是克隆血
It's cloned blood.
这些是作什么用的？
What are these for?
狼人对银过敏
Lycans are allergic to silver.
若不尽快取出子弹, 他们就会在审讯中死掉
If we don't get our bullets out quickly, they die during questioning.
接下来你要对他们作什么？
What do you do with them after?
我们把子弹放回去
We put the bullets back in.
- 事情进展的如何？ - 都准备好了
- How are things progressing?  - We're ready.
为什么你这么恨他们？
Why do you hate them so much?
我告诉过你了, 我们在作战
I've already told you, we're at war.
所以你只是按命令行事？
So you're just following orders?
为什么不回答？
Why can't you just answer the question?
好
Fine.
发生了一些事
Something was in the stable...
我们的马被撕成碎片
...tearing our horses to pieces.
我无法救出我妈妈
I couldn't have saved my mother.
和我的妹妹
or my sister.
她们的尖叫声惊醒了我
Their screams woke me.
我爸爸死在外边, 他试图去保护她们
My father died outside, trying to fend them off.
我站在门口
I stood at my door...
当我想跑到我的侄女的房间时, 我发现
...about to run to my nieces'room when...
双胞胎女孩
Twin girls.
才六岁
Barely 6 years old.
像动物似的
Butchered...
- 被屠杀了 - 天哪！
- ...like animals.  - Jesus Christ.
然后想起的下件事, 就是我已经在他怀里
The next thing I knew, I was in his arms.
战争波及我们的住所
The war had spilled into our house.
他已经跟踪狼人好几天了
He'd been tracking the Lycans for days.
他把那些人赶走也救了我
He drove them off and saved me.
- 谁？ - 维克多
- Who?  - Viktor.
我们当中最年长和最强壮的
The oldest and strongest of us.
那一夜, 他使我成为吸血鬼
That night, he made me a Vampire.
他给了我复仇的力量
He gave me the strength to avenge my family.
从那时候起, 我不再回忆过去
Since then, I've never looked back.
我看过你的照片
I saw your pictures.
那个女人是谁？你的妻子？
Who is the woman? Your wife?
也许应该看紧一点我们的兄弟
It may be wise to keep a closer eye on our cousins.
我会让瑞兹去看着他
I'll have Raze see to it immediately.
朋友, 我想我该相信你
I'm afraid that I'm going to have to place my faith in you, my friend.
但时间不多了
Time is running short.
我想转弯, 但他还是撞过来了
I tried to swerve, but he hit us anyway.
他正好把我们撞到反方向的单行道
He sent us right into the oncoming lane.
当我醒来的时候
When I came to...
我意识到引擎在前座
...I realized that part of the engine was in the front seat.
而她被钉在那里, 离我6英寸的距离
And she was pinned there, 6 inches from me...
当时情况很糟糕
...in this horrible position.
我想她吓坏了, 因为她
I think she was in shock because she just...
一遍又一遍地问我是不是受伤了
...kept asking me over and over again if I was all right.
她更担心我
She was more worried about me.
我如果能像现在一样清醒, 应该能救她
You know, if I knew then what I know now, I could have saved her.
我从未怀疑过这个
There's no doubt in my mind about that.
但她终究离我而去
But instead she died right there...
两分种后救护车赶到
...about two minutes before the ambulance arrived.
从那以后, 我便没有留恋的理由
After that, I didn't see any reason to stick around.
当我还小时, 在这跟我爷爷度过了一个夏天
I spent a summer here with my grandfather when I was a kid so...
我毕业后
After I got my degree, I just...
就远走高飞了
I took off.
我搬到这里来以忘记一切
I came over here to move on, to forget.
当时看来, 这是个不错的主意
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
你
And have you?
忘记了吗？
Moved on?
那你呢？
Have you?
我要你对我将要告诉你的事, 守口如瓶
I need you to keep what I'm about to tell you under the strictest confidence.
等一下
It can wait.
谁发动的战争？
Who started the war?
他们
They did.
或者至少我们得这样认为
Or at least that's what we've been led to believe.
挖掘历史是被禁止的
Digging into the past is forbidden.
我得回去了
I should be heading back.
那我呢？
What about me?
维克多知道怎么做, 我会回来的
Viktor will know what to do. I'll come back tomorrow night.
- 我可不想一个人在这 - 想活命就听话
- I won't stay alone.  - You will if you want to live.
我想和你一起走
I want to go with you.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
当明天月圆的时候
When the full moon rises tomorrow night...
你将会改变, 你将会去杀人, 你将会去饮血
...you will change, you will kill, and you will feed.
这是不可避免的
It's unavoidable.
我不能让你到处乱窜, 为所欲为, 对不起
I can't leave you free to roam around. I'm sorry.
一发子弹不会杀了你, 但银会防止变身
A single round won't kill you, but silver prevents transformation.
至少可以防止几个小时
At least for a few hours.
如果我没按时回来的话, 帮自己个忙
If I don't return in time, do yourself a favor.
用这个
Use it.
嗯？
Yeah?
主人 她来了
My lord. She's here.
你怎么能这么对我？让我这样难堪？
How could you do this to me? Embarrass me like this?
整个家族都知道我们有个计划
The entire coven knows that I had plans for us.
- 没有什么"我们" - 你得去维克多那里
- There is no us!  - You'll go before Viktor...
告诉他我对你说的话, 从现在起, 你要按我说的做
...and tell him exactly what I tell you to! From here on out, you'll do as I say.
还有什么不清楚的吗？
Is that in any way unclear?
来, 近点, 我的孩子
Come closer, my child.
出去
Outside.
快点, 走
Come on, move it.
没有你我迷失了方向, 主人
I've been lost without you, my lord.
克莱恩不停地纠缠我, 并乐此不疲
Constantly hounded by Kraven and his never-ending infatuation.
这是书中最古老的故事
It is the oldest story in the book.
他想拥有一样他得不到的东西
He desires the one thing he cannot have.
现在, 告诉我
Now, tell me...
为什么你相信卢西恩仍活着？
...why have you come to believe that Lucian still lives?
- 嗯 - 我给了你所需要的全部证据
- Yeah.  - I've given you all the proof you need.
只是些不连贯的思绪和影像而已, 没有别的了
Incoherent thoughts and images, nothing more.
那正是为何唤醒得由长老来完成
Which is precisely why the Awakening is performed by an elder.
你还没有具备所需的技能
You do not possess the necessary skills.
但我的确看见卢西恩了, 还打了他, 相信我
But I did see Lucian. I shot him. You must believe me.
惯例从来没被破坏过, 一次都没有
The chain has never been broken. Not once.
十四个世纪都没有
Not in 14 centuries.
自从我们这些老家伙交替出现以来, 就没有过
Not since we elders first began to leapfrog through time.
一个醒着, 两个沉睡着, 就是这样
One awake, two asleep. That's the way of it.
现在是马库斯统治的时代, 不是我的
It is Marcus' turn to reign, not mine.
- 事情有点复杂  - 但我没有选择
- There's been a complication.  - But I had no choice.
家族处于危险之中, 迈克尔是关键
The coven is in danger, and Michael is the key...
没错
Yes.
狼人
The Lycan.
求求你
Please.
给我机会让我去搞到你要的证据吧
Give me the chance to get proof you require.
好的
Fine.
我让克莱恩去搜集证据
I will leave it to Kraven to collect the proof...
如果确实有的话
...if there is any.
为什么你信任他多于信任我？
How could you trust him over me?
因为他没有被动物感染
Because he is not the one who has been tainted by an animal.
我爱你
I love you...
就像爱女儿一样, 但你让我没有选择
...like a daughter, but you leave me with no choice.
这些规矩的存在一定有其合理的理由
These rules are in place for a good reason...
而且那也是我们活这么久的唯一理由
...and they are the only reason we have survived this long.
你连一丁点的仁慈都不会得到
You will not be shown an ounce of leniency.
阿米莉亚来了以后, 理事会将开会决定你的命运
When Amelia arrives, the Council will convene and decide your fate.
你破坏了惯例, 破坏了盟约！
You have broken the chain and the Covenant!
你该受到审判！
You must be judged!
你应该听我的话, 别再管这事了
You should've listened to me and stayed out of this.
如果你运气好, 也许我能说服理事会宽恕你
Now you'll be lucky if I can convince the Council to spare your life.
告诉我
Tell me.
是你从卢西恩手臂上割下那块皮, 还是卢西恩自己割的？
Did you have the nerve to cut the skin from his arm, or did Lucian do it?
记着我的话
Mark my words.
不久, 你就会用我的眼光看待问题
Soon, you'll be seeing things my way.
不许开门, 明白吗？
No one opens this door. Understood?
我不能让我未来的女王和那个狼人再次私奔
I can't afford to have my future queen run off with that Lycan again.
该死！
Shit.
改变计划, 索伦和他的小队会把阿米莉亚接来
Change of plans. Amelia will be picked up by Soren and his team.
- 那是我们的工作！ - 从现在起不是了
- That's our job.  - Not anymore.
- 为什么你要帮我？ - 不, 我是在帮我自己
- Why are you helping me?  - I'm not. I'm helping me.
- 发生什么了？ - 警报器被触动了
- What's going on?  - The perimeter sensor's been tripped.
我们正封锁整座楼
We're locking down the mansion.
是瑟琳娜, 她跑了, 去找迈克尔了
It's Selene. She's escaped, to go to him, to Michael.
把那个狼人的头提来见我！
I want that Lycan's head on a plate.
我们得走了
We need to go.
蹲下！
Get down!
快, 走！
Go. Go.
- 跳啊！ - 你不是跟我开玩笑吧？
- Jump. - Are you fucking kidding me?
- 有消息吗？ - 只是假警报
- Any luck?  - False alarm.
如果有东西靠近围栏, 那些狗早就扑上去了
The dogs would've been all over it if anything had gotten near that fence.
- 阿米莉亚应该已经到了 - 是啊
- Amelia should have arrived by now.  - Yes.
听着, 你离开这, 去看看什么事情耽搁了她
Look, I want you to slip off the property and find out what's keeping her.
知道了
You've got it.
或许我们应该停车给他吃点药
Maybe we should pull over and dose him.
狗屁, 他会没事的, 我们就快到了
Fuck him. He'll be all right. We're almost there.
噢, 该死！他不行了, 停车, 停车！
Oh, shit. He's not gonna make it. Pull over. Pull over!
拿工具包来
Get the kit.
给他打针 快
Stick him. Stick him.
主人
My lord.
维克多找你
Viktor wants to speak with you.
主人
My lord.
我让人去叫瑟琳娜
I sent for Selene...
不是叫你
...not you.
她违抗你的命令
She's defied your orders...
从这里逃出去了, 主人
...and fled the mansion, my lord.
你的无能现在最让我费神
Your incompetence is becoming most taxing.
这不是我的错, 她很坚持
It's not my fault. She's become obsessed...
认为我是某个荒谬阴谋的主使者
...thinks that I'm at the core of some ridiculous conspiracy.
这是我的证据
And here's my proof.
现在, 你把你跟我说的话, 再跟他们说一遍
Now, I want you to tell them exactly what you told me.
好吧, 好吧
All right, all right.
我们一直在找一个特殊的人
We've been searching for someone with a special trait.
亚历山大·柯文纳斯的后裔
A direct descendant of Alexander Corvinus...
匈牙利人, 一个军阀
...Hungarian, a warlord...
在五世纪初的时候掌权
...who came to power in the early seasons of the fifth century.
恰好目睹瘟疫毁灭了他的村庄
Just in time to watch a plague ravage his village.
只有他一人活了下来
He alone survived.
不知为何, 他的身体可以改变疾病
Somehow, his body was able to change the disease...
使其对他自身有益
...mold it to his benefit.
他成为了第一个真正的不死者
He became the first true immortal.
许多年之后, 他至少有了两个孩子
And years later, he fathered at least two children...
这两个孩子也都继承了相同的特性
...who inherited this same trait.
亚历山大·柯文纳斯家族的男孩们
The sons of the Corvinus clan.
一个被蝙蝠咬了, 一个被狼咬了
One bitten by bat, one by wolf...
还有一个像人一样…独自走在由生到死的路上
...one to walk the lonely road of mortality as a human.
- 这是个荒唐的传说, 仅此而已 - 可能吧
- It's a ridiculous legend. Nothing!  - That may be...
但是我们的种族的确有一个共同的祖先
...but our species do have a common ancestor.
一个原病毒的异变
A mutation of the original virus...
和他的血脉有直接的关系
...is directly linked to his bloodline.
在那儿, 躺着一个柯文纳斯的后裔
There is a descendant of Corvinus lying there...
离你不足三英尺远
...not three feet from you.
没错
Yes.
但他已是个吸血鬼了, 我们需要纯正的来源
But he's already a Vampire. We needed a pure source...
应该没受过污染, 和最初的病毒完全一样
...untainted. An exact duplicate of the original virus...
这种元素, 我们知道
...which we learned...
是藏于他人类后代的基因密码中的
...was hidden away in the genetic code of his human descendants...
并且以潜伏的形式传递下去
...and passed along in its latent form...
自古到今
...down through the ages...
直到传给了迈克尔·柯文
...all the way to Michael Corvin.
多年来, 我们都在试图混和两个种族
For years, we tried to combine their bloodlines.
这么多年来我们都失败了
And for years we failed.
这是没用的
It was useless.
我们的两个种族, 连细胞都互相残杀
Even at the cellular level, our species seemed destined to destroy each other.
直到我们找到迈克尔
That is, until we found Michael.
他的血能带来完美的结合
The Corvinus strain allows for a perfect union.
三细胞血小板
A triple-celled platelet...
拥有不可言语的力量
...which holds unspeakable power.
不可能有完美的结合
There can be no such union.
- 就连提及到这个都是异端邪教 - 走着瞧
- And to speak of it is heresy.  - We'll see.
一旦卢西恩给他自己注射了迈克尔的血
Once Lucian has injected himself with Michael's blood.
卢西恩已经死了
Lucian is dead.
谁说的？
According to whom?
我需要你替我做些事情
I need you to do something for me.
我向你保证, 我的孩子
I can assure you, my child...
克莱恩将会偿命
...Kraven will pay with his life.
不久, 这所房子将会成为废墟
Soon, this house will lie in ruins.
- 不过你会先完蛋 - 不, 等等, 等等
- Not before you.  - No, wait. Wait.
你, 只有你自己将会知道这一事实
You and you alone will know the truth of this.
如果卢西恩能够得到一个纯种人的血
If Lucian was able to get his hands on the blood of a Pure-Born...
一个像阿米莉亚一样强大的长老
...a powerful elder like Amelia...
或者, 是你自己
...or yourself...
和迈克尔的血一起注入
...and inject it along with Michael's blood...
可恶
Abomination.
半吸血鬼
Half-Vampire...
半狼人, 但是比各自都要强
...half-Lycan, but stronger than both.
我要和卡恩说话
I need to speak with Kahn.
主人
My lord...
理事会成员已经被暗杀了
...the Council members have been assassinated.
- 阿米莉亚怎么样了？ - 他们放光了她的血
- What of Amelia?  - They bled her dry.
已经开始了
It has already begun.
我为怀疑你感到抱歉
I'm sorry I doubted you.
别害怕, 我的孩子, 你将会得到赦免
Fear not, my child, absolution will be yours...
只要你杀死了柯文纳斯的后代
...the moment you kill the descendant of Corvinus, this...
迈克尔
...Michael.
已经给你注射了阻止变身的酶
You've been given an enzyme to stop the change.
晕眩的状态一会儿就会消失的
It may take a little time for the grogginess to dissipate.
够了！
That's enough!
去看看瑞兹怎么还没来？
Just go and see what's keeping Raze, will you?
我真的要说抱歉
I really must apologize.
他真的需要好好学学礼貌
He's in desperate need of a lesson in manners.
讲到礼貌 我在哪里呢? 请原谅
Speaking of manners, where are mine? Forgive me.
我是卢西恩
I'm Lucian.
我要走
I need to go.
我要回去
I need to get back.
不能回去
There's no going back.
哪儿都不能去
There's no going anywhere.
吸血鬼一看见你就会杀了你, 因为你是
The Vampires will kill you on sight. Just for being what you are.
我们当中的一个
One of us.
你是我们当中的一个
You are one of us.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
- 你在干什么？ - 让这场冲突结束
- What are you doing?  - Bringing an end to this conflict.
你的战争与我无关
Your war, it has nothing to do with me.
我的战争？
My war?
不！
No!
不！不！
No! No!
索妮亚！
Sonja!
他们逼你看着她死去
They forced you to watch her die.
索妮亚！
Sonja.
这才是引起战争的原因
That's what started the war.
我看见它发生就像我身临其境一般
I saw it happen as if I were there.
我们曾经是奴隶
We were slaves once.
吸血鬼白天的守卫者
The daylight guardians of the Vampires.
我出生在奴隶的家庭
I was born in servitude...
但是我不憎恨吸血鬼
...yet I harbored them no ill will.
我甚至娶了一个吸血鬼作我的新娘
I even took a Vampire for my bride.
我们的结合
It was forbidden...
是被禁止的
...our union.
维克多害怕血统混合
Viktor feared a blending of the species.
非常害怕
Feared it so much...
他杀了她
...he killed her.
他自己的女儿
His own daughter...
活活烧死了她
...burnt alive...
只是因为她爱我
...for loving me.
这是他的战争
This is his war...
维克多的
...Viktor's...
而且他从六百年前就开始
...and he's spent the last 600 years...
消灭我的族人
...exterminating my species.
他们会对瑟琳娜做什么呢？
What are they gonna do to Selene?
我们有客人来了
We have company.
- 我想我们说好了的 - 耐心点
- I thought we had a deal.  - Patience.
克莱恩
Kraven.
这些事应该私下谈
These are matters to be discussed in private.
把我们的客人护送到楼下去吧
Please escort our guests downstairs.
理事会被消灭了
The Council has been destroyed.
你很快就会得到
Soon, you will have it all.
伟大的族群以及和狼人达成的永久和平条约
Both great covens and an ironclad peace treaty with the Lycans.
当战利品到手后, 我不会忘记那些我信任的人
Who I trust will not be forgotten when the spoils are tabulated.
维克多已经醒了, 你以为我还能控制吗？
How do you expect me to assume control now that Viktor's awake?
没人能打败他, 我们说话时他正变得更强大
There's no defeating him. He grows stronger as we speak.
这就是为什么我需要迈克尔
And that is precisely why I need Michael.
如果维克多很容易就会被弄死
If Viktor were so easy to dispatch...
几世纪前, 你自己就会干掉他了
...you'd have done it yourself centuries ago.
关闸！快！
Exit shaft! Move it!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
噢, 他妈的！
Oh, shit!
是维克多
It's Viktor.
是的
Yes.
如果你干好自己该干的事, 他仍旧在休眠中
And if you had done your job, he'd still be in hibernation.
妈的, 瑞兹到底在哪儿？
Where the hell is Raze?
还有别的出路吗？
Is there another way out?
我猜你从未想过…要流血才能赢得胜利
I guess it didn't occur to you that you'll have to bleed to pull off this coup.
别想逃
Don't even think about leaving.
硝酸银！我打赌你没想到这点
Silver nitrate. Bet you weren't expecting that.
快, 快点！快上！快！
Come on! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
卢西恩
Lucian.
瑟琳娜！
Selene!
还不行
Not yet.
我要带你走, 维克多就要来了
I have to get you out. Viktor's on his way.
他不希望一个狼人能活下来
And he won't be satisfied until every Lycan's dead.
他们也会因为你帮了我而杀了你的
They'll kill you too, just for helping me.
这我知道
I know.
我知道导致这场战争的原因了
I know what started the war.
够了！跟我来！
That's enough. You're coming with me!
我希望我能活着看到维克多结束你的生命
I hope I live to see Viktor choke the life from you!
我打赌你会
I bet you do.
但让我告诉你件事, 关于你深爱着的黑暗之父
But let me tell you a little something about your beloved dark father.
他就是杀死你全家的凶手
He's the one who killed your family.
不是狼人
Not the Lycans.
他从不遵守自己定下的规矩
Never could follow his own rules.
他说无法忍受牲畜的味道
Said he couldn't abide the taste of livestock.
所以他偶尔出去贪婪地喝人血
So every once in a while, he went out and gorged himself on human blood.
我替他保守秘密
I kept his secrets...
收拾残局
...cleaned up the mess.
就是他
But it was he...
蹑手蹑脚地走进一个个房间
...who crept room to room...
杀死了你最亲的人
...dispatching everyone close to your heart.
但是, 当他看到你
But when he got to you...
他忍不住想喝干你的血
...he just couldn't bear the thought of draining you dry.
可是你让他想起了他最珍爱的索妮亚
You, who reminded him so much of his precious Sonja...
他亲手处决的女儿
...the daughter he condemned to death.
- 说谎 - 信不信由你
- Lies.  - Believe what you want.
快走
Now come on.
到我身边来
Your place is by my side.
那就死吧
So be it.
咬他！
Bite him!
半吸血鬼
Half-Vampire...
半狼人
...half-Lycan...
但是比两个都要强
...but stronger than both.
你到底在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
你可以杀死我
You may have killed me...
堂兄
...cousin.
但是我的愿望
But my will...
已经实现
...is done regardless.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
克莱恩在哪儿？
Where's Kraven?
原谅我, 我的孩子
Forgive me, my child.
不是狼人
It wasn't the Lycans.
是你
It was you.
走开
Leave us.
你怎么能骗我
How could you bear my trust...
是你杀了我全家
...knowing that you'd killed my family?
是的
Yes.
我从你身边夺走很多
I have taken from you.
但我给你的更多
But I have given so much more.
这不是公平交易吗？我赐予你生命永生的礼物？
Is it not a fair trade, the life I have granted you? The gift of immortality?
还有你女儿的生命？
And the life of your daughter?
你自己的骨肉？
Your own flesh and blood?
我爱我的女儿
I loved my daughter!
但是她怀了孽种
But the abomination growing in her womb...
那是对我和家族的背叛
...was a betrayal of me and of the coven!
我所作的都是为了保护我的种族
I did what was necessary to protect the species...
而且我不得不再一次这么做了
...as I am forced to do yet again.
不
No!
你的死期到了
Time to die.
虽然我无法预言未来
Though I cannot predict the future...
但今晚的结局会在以后的许多年中
...the consequences of tonight will reverberate through the halls...
给族里造成巨大影响
...of both great covens for many years to come.
两个吸血鬼长老死了
Two Vampire elders have been slain...
有一个是我亲手杀死的
...one by my own hand.
不久马库斯将会继位
Soon, Marcus will take the throne.
怨恨和报复将弥漫在夜空中
And a tide of anger and retribution will spill out into the night.
分歧将被消除
Differences will be set aside.
人人都会效忠
Allegiances will be made.
不久
And soon...
我将会被追杀
...I will become the hunted.